

#### DATA SCIENCE/ENGINEERING · US CITIZEN

Boston, MA

【(+1) 978-201-5748 | ☑robbenzmann@gmail.com | 🏠 robbmann.io | ☑ renzmann | 🛅 renzmann

# **Summary**

Sr. Data Scientist with a track record of empowering data science teams to do more, run faster, and build robust software. I specialize in the gap between business analytics and deployment engineering to help both teams work better together.

# Work Experience

### **Algorex Health Technologies**

Boston, MA

SR. DATA SCIENTIST

Mar. 2021 - Present

- Led modeling of COVID-19 vaccine adoption rates in vulnerable populations around the greater Boston area to give targeted outreach recommendations for over 2,000 plan members. (Survival analysis in SQL+Python)
- Transitioned the data science team to AWS SageMaker on more than a dozen client accounts, saving \$40,000 annually in infrastructure costs and reduced the onboarding time for new analysts from 3 days to 15 minutes. (Docker, Terraform, Jenkins)
- Principal developer of the internal Python + SQL software development kit, which optimized the engineering environment installation time from 45 minutes to 30 seconds and removed collaboration barriers between data scientists, engineers, and project managers. (Presto SQL, Jinja, Bash, Make, poetry-python)

antuit.ai Frisco, TX

DATA SCIENTIST (PRICING AND MARKETING)

Sep. 2017 - Mar. 2021

- Wrote an optimization algorithm for strategic pricing of consumer healthcare products in 11 countries, modeling more than \$5Bn in revenue across 8 product categories per country. (Python, Numpy, nlopt)
- Created ETL pipelines that prepared 1+ TB consumer healthcare product sales for a data warehouse. I also designed over 50 custom views in the warehouse that reduced the average data scientist query time from 5 minutes to a few seconds and reduced the team's query costs by 80 percent. (Spark SQL/pyspark, Kubernetes, Azure)
- Solved problems across three clients related to optimal pricing, mixed-effects/hierarchical modeling, personalized product recommendations, customer churn, and lifetime value (CLTV) for over 1MM program members. In these projects I had the opportunity to benchmark traditional methods like survival and mixed-effects modeling against newer, more sophisticated techniques, such as using an LSTM to predict cross-product purchasing behavior. (python, scipy, R, lmer, numpy)

#### **Core Skills**

### **Tools & Languages**

I DABBLE IN MANY OTHERS - BUT THESE ARE MY BREAD & BUTTER

- Python, SSH, Git 5 yoe; specializing in DS with pandas, numpy, matplotlib; modeling experience with xgboost, scikit-learn, and hyperopt
- GNU/Unix, Bash, Make, SQL, Dask, Spark 3 yoe
- AWS Athena (Presto SQL), PostgreSQL, SQLite 2 yoe

#### **Tech Stack**

WHERE AND HOW I'VE DEPLOYED THINGS

- · Azure, AWS 2 yoe
- Databricks, SageMaker, Docker, Terraform

### **Education**

Miami University Oxford, OH

• Master's topic: *The Container Method for Triangle-induced Hypergraphs* 

Sep. 2011 - May 2017

Sep. 2011 - May 2015

• 2017 Journal award

B.A. Music

MASTER OF MATHEMATICS

• Presented *The (ab)surd Golden Ratio* at TEDx Miami University on the dubious connections between art and the Fibonacci sequence: https://youtu.be/0vVxL60YFJU (325k views)

Miami University Oxford, OH

4-year music scholarship.

• Focus in music technology, recording, and audio acoustic design.

June 7, 2022 Robert Enzmann · Résumé 1